Mobile: +33 (0)6 87 79 01 99

Email: besconda(at)gmail.com

Online: https://redref.github.io/self-resume/



Thanks to 10 years of experience in system engineering, in many different contexts and goals, I have a skill set allowing me to be pertinent in infrastructure, application operations and data workflows either in datacenter or cloud infrastructure.

I am looking forward to integrate a team to design complete solutions, with always performance, scalibility and simplicity in mind.

#### Skills and Technologies

#### Infrastructure / Deploy

Terraform GCP/GKE Kubernetes (onprem or cloud) Jenkins Artifactory Puppet/Ansible/Saltstack Gitlab/Jenkins

#### **Monitoring / Tracing**

Fluentd Prometheus Grafana loki/tempo OpenTSDB ELK stack

#### **Development / Frameworks**

Kubernetes operators Django App Engine

#### Languages

Go Python Shell

#### **Databases / Storage**

Mongo Elasticsearch Hadoop Kafka Cassandra PostgresSQL MariaDB Ceph MooseFS

### HPC

Slurm Infiniband RDMA CUDA

#### **Education**

# Professional degree (Licence) in "Networks administration and security"

Technology degree (DUT) in "Networks and telecommunications" 2007

#### Experiences

## DevOps

since 2020

2008

Altair Engineering

Technologies: Kubernetes, Docker, Mongo, Python, Grafana Stack, K3S, Gitlab

Manage infrastuctur and release for a multi-cloud ressources deployment software in micro-services (bursting or dedicated use cases). Manage cloud tests configurations on 7 clouds, deploy and support owned deployments and support clients.

Develop and deploy integrations with off-the-shelf softwares for monitoring, tracing or hooking. Projects:

- Make all micro-services highly-available in kubernetes deployments
- Deploy software on-premise with K3S
- Refactor tool managing differences between compose/kubernetes development flavor (github.com/altairengineering/pkr)
- Migrate tests from Jenkins to GitlabCI

# "System Reliability Engineer"

2018 to 2019

Blablacar (Paris)

Technologies: Kubernetes, Docker, Rkt, Go, Prometheus, Nginx, BGP, Istio

In a team of 3, responsible to design, choose and reliability of databases clusters: MariaDB, Hadoop, Vertica, Cassandra, Redis ... and data manipulation tools: Kafka, Kafka Connect, Airflow. In a bigger team, participate in infrastructure, app deployment and project specific solutions. Projets:

- Revamp API caching layer (Nginx) in a reliable way (multi-layered)
- Migrate databases to GKE, define containers, deployment policies, monitoring, backups ...
- Redesign logging stack

## System engineer in HPC/BigData

2014 to 2018

Ministry of defense (Paris)

Technologies: Puppet, Linux, Python, Django, DRF, Ceph, Infiniband, GPU

Choose hardware according to software benchmarks and problems.

Provision, configure, patch and maintain "bare metal" hardware clusters.

Integrate and optimise HPC and BigData softwares for performance.

Design and develop tools as daemons, APIs or webservices to manage platforms (Python)

Analyse customers applications to optimise workloads.

## System engineer in e-commerce

2013 to 2014

Galeries Lafayette (Paris)

Technologies: Apache, Varnish, Tomcat, Oracle, Hybris, Graphite

Manage and maintain the 3-tier web platform and product publishing workflows.

Design and maintain delivery architecture with test platforms and automatic build processes.

Integrate metrology tools used by the platform capacity planning and marketing.

## System engineer in HPC

2013

OVH GS - Oxalya (Paris)

Technologies: Linux, Slurm, Lustre, Infiniband, GPU Nvidia

Install, deploy and maintain dedicated HPC clusters in customers offices.

Integrate a "software as a service" offer.

Compile, optimise and benchmark computation softwares.

## System administrator

2010 to 2012

DCNS (Cherbourg)

Technologies: Linux, Oracle, JBOSS, Apache, Tomcat, Java, Centreon, Control-M

Install and maintain industrial applications (stock and workflows) and daily data processes. Develop tools to ensure a safe and smooth delivery installation process.

## System administrator "Intelligent Network"

2008 à 2010

Alcatel-Lucent

Assignments: Bell M (Canada), OTE (Grèce), Orange (R.Dominicaine).

Technologies: Solaris, Oracle, Switching

Install and deliver IN application cluster and services on customer site.

## Network administrator (internship)

2008

MMF Services (Quéven)

Configure new network stack with internal needs.

Integrate web-services as alternatives to VPN.

## PHP developer (internship)

2007

Solstys (Lannion)

Integrate WebDav protocol in the CMS product by emulation in PHP.

#### **Interests**

Trail running

Development and new technologies (home system, deep learning algorithms, ...)

Online gaming